Hey! Quit slackin' off!
أنت، لا تتقاعس في العمل
Okay.
...حسنًا
Hey, cabin boys! After sweeping, wash the windows!
أيّها العاملان، نظّفا النّوافذ بعد أن تنتهوا من الأرضيّة
Yes, sir!
عُلِم
– One! Two! Three! Four!
واحد، اثنان، ثلاثة، أربعة
I can't stand this. Forget Koby— why do I have to be a cabin boy?!
!لا أطيق هذا، دعك عن كوبي... لماذا عليّ أن أكون عاملًا؟
Dammit! I only ended up here because of that Straw Hat!
!سُحقًا! هذا كلّه بسبب قبّعة القش ذاك
It's all because of Straw Hat that I'm stuck doing this crap!
!أنا متورط في كلّ هذا العمل الهراء الآن بسبب قبّعة القش
Helmeppo.
،هيلميبو-سان
What do you want?! Don't act like we're friends!
!ماذا تريد؟! لا تلمسني وكأنّنا أصدقاء
Nothing good comes from blaming Luffy for everything that happens.
ليس من الصواب لوم لوفي-سان على كلّ شيء هكذا
For a long time, you lived protected by your father's influence.
عشتَ حياتك لوقت طويل تستغلّ سلطة والدك
But from now on, we need to face forward and seek our own dreams!
لكن ابتداءً من الآن علينا أن نتقدّم للأمام، ونبحث عن أحلامنا بنفسنا
What are you...?
...إنّك
I have a dream.
لديّ حلم
Someday, I will be a Marine officer who cracks down on bad guys!
سأصبح ضابط بحريّة يومًا وأُطيح بكلّ الأشرار
What are you going on about?!
!لا تغتر بنفسك
A wimp like you becoming an officer for the Marines?!
!جبان مثلك يصبح ضابط بحريّة؟! لن يحدث ذلك أبدًا
I will do it!
!بل سيحدث
I decided on it after seeing how Luffy lives his life!
!بعد رؤيتي كيف يعيش لوفي-سان حياته، اتّخذتُ قراري أيضًا
This is what I've decided, so if I die, then fine by me!
قرّرتُ أن أصبح كذلك، لذا لا أمانع القتال والموت من أجل ذلك
So just like Luffy, I've made up my mind to risk everything
لذا قرّرتُ أن أصبح مثل لوفي-سان وأضع حياتي على المحكّ
and pursue a goal of my own!
!لأسعى نحو طموحي
You see? So let's work hard together!
أرأيت؟ لذلك دعنا نعمل بجدّ معًا
Screw you!
!هراء
How dare you lecture me?!
!أتحاضرني؟! منذ متى وأنت أعلى شأنًا منّي؟
What could you possibly learn from that despicable Straw Hat?!
!ما الّذي قد تتعلّمه من قبّعة القشّ البغيض ذاك؟
Don't insult Luffy!
!لا تتحدّث بسوء عن لوفي-سان
I haven't said anything wrong!
!لم أقل أيّ شيء خاطئ
Wrong or not, you still piss me off!
!حتّى إن كان ذلك صحيحًا، فما زلت تثير غضبي
Helmeppo! Please! You have to be realistic.
!هيلميبّو-سان! عُد إلى رشدك لو سمحت
Look who's talking!
!وكأنّه يحقّ لك الحديث
Take this!
!خذ هذه
Get ahold of yourself!
!استيقظ
Huh? What's going on?!
ما الأمر؟ ماذا يحدث؟
– W-We're sorry! – We're sorry!
!نـ-نعتذر
Really? The explosion earlier was because of you?
ماذا؟ ذلك الانفجار قبل قليل كان من فعلتكما؟
So then they kicked you out of the Marines?
طُرِدتما من البحريّة إذًا؟
Thank you.
بالهناء والشفاء
No, we managed to avoid being discharged.
لا، تمكّنّا من تجنّب الطّرد
But now we're under a fifty-year contract with no pay.
لكنّنا وافقنا على العمل مجّانًا لخمسين سنة
Getting canned would've been a mercy.
لكان الطّرد أفضل بكثير من ذلك
Attention!
!انتباه
I will now fill you in on our current mission!
سَأُعلِمك الآن عن مهمّتنا الحاليّة
– Hey! – What do you want?!
!انظر
D-Daddy...
...أ-أبي
Morgan, a former Marine captain, is to be sent to headquarters
سيُرسل نقيب البحريّة السّابق مورغان لمقرّ البحريّة
to face a court-martial for the crimes of military exploitation and civilian torment!
ليخضع لمحاكمة عسكريّة على خلفية جرائم الاستغلال العسكريّ
Today's mission is his transfer and delivery to Vice Admiral Garp!
!نقله وتوصيله لنائب الأميرال غارب هي مهمّتنا لهذا اليوم
I am Captain "Axe-Hand" Morgan of the Marines!
!أنا نقيب البحريّة يد الفأس مورغان
Scum without rank or status should kneel before me!
!لا يملك عديمو الرّتبة أصحاب المكانة الوضيعة الحقّ لعصياني
This was the only outcome, wasn't it?
لا مهرب من الأمر، صحيح؟
I'm not denying that he should be court-martialed or whatever.
عليه أن يُحاكم عسكريًّا أو مهما كان
He deserves what's coming to him, after all.
...قبل كل شيء، يستحقّ ما حدث له
But even so, I used to respect him.
لكن لأصدقك القول، كنت لا أزال أحترمه مع ذلك
Damn it!
!سُحقًا
Why?!
!لماذا؟
Tell me, do you think they'll execute him?
أخبرني، هل تعتقد أنّهم سيعدمونه؟
Th-That's...
...ذ-ذلك
There's probably no getting around that either, huh?
ربّما لا مهرب من ذلك أيضًا، صحيح؟
That's just how Daddy is.
...بالنّظر لأفعال أبي
Helmeppo...
...هيلميبّو-سان
All hands on deck!
!فليجتمع الجميع
Fall in!
!اصطفّوا
– It's Vice Admiral Garp! – It's Garp the Fist!
إنّه نائب الأميرال غارب
So that's Marine Headquarters' Vice Admiral Garp the Fist!
ذلك الرجل هو نائبُ أميرالٍ في مقرّ البحرية إذًا، غارب القبضة
Traveling all over the Grand Line, he's the hero of the seas!
!بطل البحار الّذي أبحر عبر الغراند لاين
Vice Admiral Garp, thank you for personally coming all this way!
يا نائب الأميرال غارب، شكرًا على مجيئك إلى هنا شخصيًّا
We hereby deliver to you Morgan!
!ها نحن نسلّم مورغان لك
Stop, Helmeppo!
!توقّف يا هيلميبّو-سان
Umm... Vice Admiral Garp?
يا نائب الأميرال غارب؟
Vice Admiral Garp!
!يا نائب الأميرال غارب
Quiet!
!اصمت
I hear you.
أستطيع سماعك
I've been up for five days now.
...بقيتُ مستيقظًا لخمسة أيّام حتّى الآن
Thank you for your hard work, sir!
!بوركتَ على عملك الدؤوب يا سيّدي
It's no big deal since I'm trying for a new doughnut-eating record.
...كلاّ، كنتُ أحاول كسر رقم قياسيّ جديد في أكل الدّونات
Sir?
ماذا؟
But a lack of rest and sleep is getting to me after the 842nd one.
...لكنّ قلّة النّوم والرّاحة قد جعلاني أدوخ خلال تناول القطعة 842
Old man, cut the sleeping act.
أيّها العجوز، كفّ عن التّظاهر بالنّوم
Everybody freeze!
!لا تتحرّكوا
Move and I'll hack up this cabin boy and feed him to the sharks!
!حركة واحدة وسأشقّ هذا العامل العامل وأطعمه للقروش
D-Daddy!
!أ-أ-أبي
Please stop!
توقّف رجاءً! أوَليس هيلميبّو-سان ابنك؟
Son?! I don't need such a thing!
ابنٌ؟ لا أحتاجه
What I want is freedom!
ما أريده هي الحرية
I'll smash him to a bloody pulp if need be!
!وفي سبيل ذلك، أنا مستعدّ لإغراق المكان بدمائه إن اقتضى الأمر
D-Daddy...
...أ-أبي
H-Help me!
!الـ-النّجدة
So long, suckers!
!مع السّلامة أيّها الأغبياء
Helmeppo!
!هيلميبّو-سان
Ready the cannon!
!جهّزوا المدفع
Load! Aim!
!لقّموه! صوّبوا
Target: 16 degrees starboard.
!الهدف... 16 درجة جهة الميمنة !المسافة... 8263! استعداد
P-P-Please wait!
!ا-انتظروا رجاءً
That's dangerous!
!هذا خطر
– What are you doing?! – Get down from there!
!ما الّذي تفعله؟
P-Please don't shoot! My friend...
...لا-لا تطلقوا رجاءً! صديقي
My friend's onboard!
!صديقي على متن القارب
Move.
.ابتعد
No!
أرفض
Then I'll cut you down!
سأقطعك إذًا
That's much better than just abandoning my friend!
ذلك أفضل بكثيرٍ من أن أتخلى عن صديقي بكل بساطة
Please! I'll go capture him myself!
أرجوك، سأذهب للقبض عليه بنفسي
Come back, you idiot!
!عُد أيها الغبي
There's no way you can capture him!
!مُحالٌ عليك إمساكه
Just let him go.
لندعه يذهب
He's either a complete lunatic, or...
...قد يكون مغفّلًا أو
What do we do?!
ما العمل الآن؟
What's with all the racket? I'm finally awake.
...ما كلّ هذه الجلبة؟ أفقتُ أخيرًا
Vice Admiral Garp, we thought you were a goner!
يا نائب الأميرال غارب، ظننتُه نال منك تمامًا
Huh?! Who's a goner?!
ماذا؟ نالوا من أحدهم؟
I missed it because I was asleep! Where's the victim?!
لم أر ما حدث لأنّني كنتُ نائمًا، من هو؟
Me?
كان أنا؟
I'm free!
!أنا حر
Just you watch! The world will kneel before me once again!
!راقب فحسب، سيركع العالم أمامي ثانية
Today, I begin a new life as the ruler of the Morgan Kingdom!
!اليوم هو بداية جديدة لمملكة مورغان المولودة حديثًا
Now! Set our course west!
!والآن، عدّل مسارنا غربًا
What are you doing?! I said to set course due west!
!ما الّذي تفعله؟! قلتُ لك أن تعدّل مسارنا غربًا
No!
!أرفض
I'll have no part in this!
!لا أريد الاشتراك في هذا
Despite what happened, he still covered for us!
!لقد دافع عنّي بعدما حدث
Even when getting sacked by the Marines would end his dream!
!فعلها وهو يعلم أنّ حُلمه سيُدمّر إن طرد من البحريّة
After all that, he's still protecting me! I can do it, too!
!لكنّه حماني على الرّغم من ذلك
I'm going to capture you, Dad! Just give up–
!أبي، سألقي القبض عليك -سلم نفسك رجا
Are you dim?! Who do you think you're talking to, huh?!
هل أنت غبيّ؟ إلى من تتحدّث في رأيك؟
What can useless scum like you do to me?!
ما الّذي يستطيع حثالة مثلك أن يفعله بي؟
Dammit!
!سُحقًا
Know your place, you pathetic insect!
!الزم حدودك أيّها الحشرة الذّليلة
As if I'd ever listen to you!
،وكأنّني سأصغي لك
I'm the one who decides how I'll live!
!أنا من يقرّر كيف أعيش حياتي
Quit getting the wrong idea! What can a piece of scum like you do?!
!كفّ عن فهم الأمر بشكل خاطئ! ماذا بإمكان بحثالة وحده فعله؟
He isn't alone!
!إنّه ليس وحده
You!
!أنت
Morgan!
!مورغان
Pathetic! Pathetic! Pathetic!
!هراء! هراء! هرااء
So what if a couple of insects are swarming together?!
!ماذا بمقدور حشرتين فعله؟
Get in my way, and I'll end you both in one fell swoop!
!اعترضا طريقي وسأقطّعكما إربًا
I'm sorry you got dragged into this when you tried to save me.
...أنا آسف لأنّ الأمور آلت لهذا المآل بعد أن أتيت لإنقاذي
What are you talking about?
عمّ تتحدّث؟
Aren't we friends?
أوَلسنا صديقان؟
Koby...
...كوبي
You damn insects aren't even worth killing.
،حشرتان لعينتان لا تستحقّان حتّى القتل
Never show yourselves to me again!
!لا تظهرا وجهيكما لي ثانية
Morgan!
!مورغان
I'll let you go for today,
!سأسمح لك بالفرار اليوم
but someday I will surpass you!
!لكنّني سأتغلّب عليك يومًا
Someday, I will catch you!
!سأقبض عليك يومًا
Just you wait!
!انتظر فحسب
Please forgive my poor supervision!
!اعذر إشرافي الضّعيف رجاءً
Letting him flee is the biggest blunder in my life!
!السّماح للسّجين بالهرب هو أكبر خطأ ارتكبته في حياتي
We're very sorry, sir!
!التمس منّا العذر يا سيدي
These two are now forever barred from military service!
!بعد ما حدث، سيُطردا مدى الحياة
You two truly are lost causes.
يا لكما من فاشلَين فعلًا
I doubt anyone anywhere would take you in now.
أشكّ أنّ هنالك أحدٌ قد يقبل بكما في العالم
And if we turn you loose, you'd be a nuisance to all.
...وستكونان مجرّد عبء على الجميع إن تركناكما
You leave me no choice. Come with me to Marine Headquarters!
ما باليدّ حيلة، تعاليا معي لمقرّ البحريّة
Vice Admiral! You're taking them with you to Marine Headquarters?!
يا نائب الأميرال، ستأخذهما معك لمقرّ البحريّة؟
Am I not allowed?
ألا يمكنني؟
No, do as you please.
...بـ-بلى، لم أقصد هذا
Any objections, you two?
هل تعارضان هذا؟
If you want to run away, now's your chance.
هذه فرصتكما إن كنتما تريدان الهرب
Though I have no intention of letting you say no.
رغم أنّ لا نيّة لي بالسّماح لكما بالرّفض على أيّ حال
My, oh my, what an odd day this has been!
يا إلهي، يا له من يوم غريب
What?! Marine Headquarters?!
ماذا؟ مقرّ البحريّة؟
Yeah. Vice Admiral Garp seems to be as eccentric as people say.
نعم. يقول النّاس إنّ نائب الأميرال غارب غريب الأطوار
But doesn't he have an exceptional reputation?
لكنّ حضرته ذو شأنٍ عالٍ، أليس كذلك؟
Yeah, you have no idea.
نعم، عالٍ جدًّا
Then those two must show a lot of promise.
ما يعني أن ذينك الاثنين مستقبلهما واعد
Stupid! Stupid! Stupid! Stupid! Stupid!
!غبيّ! غبيّ! غبيّ! غبيّ! غبيّ
Why did you let them go without saying anything?!
لماذا سمحتَ لهما بالذّهاب دون قول أيّ شيء؟
I... wanted to play with them more.
أردتُ... اللّعب معهما أكثر
I wanted to talk to them more.
...أردتُ الحديث معهما أكثر
I was learning how to cook so I could make them tasty lunch boxes!
!كنتُ أتعلّم كيف أطبخ لأستطيع طهي غداء شهيّ لهما
I didn't even get to say goodbye!
!لم يتسنّ لي حتّى... أن أودّعهما
Ah... Um...
...عفوًا
Why did they leave?!
!لماذا غادرا؟
Ah, I'm sorry! Forgive me!
!أعتذر، سامحيني
Rika, that's enough. Leave him alone.
ريكا، هذا يكفي، دعيه وشأنه
Don't worry. They'll surely be back... once they become fine officers.
لا تقلقي، سيعودان بكلّ تأكيد... بعد أن يصبحا ضابطين جيّدين
But at any rate,
،بهذا المعدّل
can we really become Marines by doing things like this?
مقر البحرية
This might be that old dog's hobby, you know.
قد تكون هذه هواية ذلك الكلب العجوز
Hobby?
هواية؟
Yup. It's called "the retired geezer's torment of youths."
«صحيح، هواية تُدعى «تعذيب العجوز المتقاعد للشّباب
Don't you think he's shifty and strange enough for that?
ألا تعتقد أنّ ذلك ممكن بما أنّه ماكر وغريب أطوار؟
Shut up, birds!
!اخرسي أيّتها الطّيور